all right we were talking about secret
special qualities opportunity and we
raised the third one and it it means
mother kept on you got that
okay okay chem gets annoyed a moba
mentality so when you take refuge you
can have three different thoughts about
those jewels they're not too late to
another this drove for those of you
studying Tibetan doesn't mean libery it
means to cross over with the sentence
turner yes so when you are trying to
cross over a large body of water like
the Pacific Ocean and go from San
Francisco to Shanghai TripIt um you need
a captain of the ship who knows how to
drive it called truth um and you need a
ship and young Detroit your car and you
need people to go with you to help you
get there and then we can think of some
Gainey chip an onion core Chama
now the next sentence is very important
son Gainey children young court cello
your relationship to the Buddha
who's that in this metaphor you know
your relationship to the captain should
be choppered onion corn make offerings
bribe them to take you on the boat get
you across okay that's that's what we do
with the captain
cheers argue long with each other but in
this case the Dharma is not a person
here's where he says the Dharma is
something to be achieved inside of you
okay so the first jewel you are making
offerings to a person are being the
second jewel is something you have to
find inside of you something else to
plan inside of your understanding
emptiness right third jewel ganden de
soutien to go probable and then the
third joel is people you want to be
friends with who are people who remember
seeds all the time you want to hang out
with the
like that okay to reinforce what you
know okay
duplicate bunny day some Lachlan
mashallah Sheela is a beautiful verb in
Tibet means surrender your soul to to
these three okay to practicing those
three okay offering to the Buddha trying
to get the Dharma inside of you and then
choosing wisely with your friends okay
and make it your heart's work make it
your life's work to do that
that's called Shola yeah it isn't
the other ship is inside of you that's
pretty cool Jenga company how do you
think about them Sun gates on the - eh
you should recite the Sutra that starts
with Arya Buddha under 21 I taught you
that suture before reaching right small
suture and that's how you should think
of these three jewels don't you get some
machine going looking intentionally then
just think about how cool they are okay
and that's how we should think of them
when we're alone when we're on the bus
when we're driving you know when you
have a quiet moment then just think of
how cool they are especially the broom
and that's the future I gave you so if
you want to you know when I have stuff
that I want to remember I just put it up
on my computer and I take a picture of
it and then I it's on my phone when I
want to read that you to a community
okay it doesn't take much space on your
phone this is a little too hot but
Mike's a little too hot the mic is too
hot yeah okay all right so I taught you
that to talk to you what it means I'm
going to skip through that somebody
should translate the commentary he yaks
okay six coffee cinnamon element get
awakened from you something Iike such
agglutination ago how do these three
jewels act to multiply our good karma
son game you can see let kinesin Impella
with regard to the Buddha jewel just
having faith in one person multiplies
your glucose can give me cuz I mumble
adenosine Impella and with the Sangha
you are multiplying your karma by doing
it with more people there's more people
good as one person Buddha jewel is one
person in this case and Sangha jewel is
many people roughly Sangha jewel is
anyone who understands the pen or better
okay
sinem pelvic language I'm Kendrick
Kentucky wanna cheer down again he says
the Buddha and Sangha are people but
chilly gossip Miami wanted to send
intelligible but with the damage you
know you are multiplying your karma with
something that's not a person with an
idea okay
David or na Young Saeng Gila comes a
drawn a chaplain and rejoice on English
any liability achieve as well so when
you think about going for refuge to the
Buddha
you're thinking about offerings I don't
like to say offerings because it reminds
me of
and only the monks can offer you're not
allowed to offer and you know things
like that I like to think of it as thank
you notes to the Buddha okay it's just
thank-you notes to the Buddha okay if
someone really did something nice to you
then you give them thank you melons
right and that's all it's not good can
you hear me okay did it it's okay okay
my ears are out I don't know why
okay turn around you like a pitcher
basil but the way to go to refuge to the
Dharma jewel is just to understand the
pen and then you are taking refuge okay
so it's not something you do it in sense
it's not something you do on your knees
and a temple it's something we do when
your husband yells at you when you come
home all your wife mr. Dunn okay all
right I said I kept saying husband and
then this guy in Guangzhou races handy
said you don't mention wife ever wife
also ordered okay next is called going
for shelter by accepting the shelter
Sibugay llama gonna come to drona soon
gain
Sanjana cuts kimbap Oh children
Gananoque young to be toxic in India so
there's an idea that you accept these as
three refuges you accept them as refuge
okay first one you accept the Buddha
this is interesting
okay listen not as a reference but as
the person who teaches you what is
restless okay so you go to the Buddha
you go for Russia to the Buddha it means
you go for refuge because he teaches you
the
okay got it so you're not really you're
going to have because he's going to
teach you the damage oh okay chill not
Gavin Gavin low means that's the real
refuge of the three the real protection
is number two of the three jewels the
real protection is to understand the pen
understand the husband's coming from you
okay that's real protection why human
nature is to respond to violence with
violence your husband calls it stupid
you say no you're stupid this is human
nature okay
and real protection when you follow your
human nature you say back to the husband
me frontal male look no not this is
refundable here the right pocket Hank
I'm not then that's human nature when
you do that you do yourself and that
plans another thing to have your husband
your life so it becomes a cycle we look
like so the actual protection the
highest protection is the idea that I
shouldn't plant another seed I don't
want to plant and understand okay and
you just shut up is your husband a
frontal yes is he stupid yes all
husbands are stupid but you don't have
to say it everybody knows things okay
just don't say anything okay then we
don't plant another stupid husband okay
Dan Katie Markum do potatoes to kill
everything and then you accept Sangha as
your friends people who can help you
okay
especially people who are seeing
emptiness Christian yes
I can't resist and we have seen your
explanation of the Ganges yes we're
doing what the vision is
yeah we're doing all that yeah exactly
not not right it assumes depending on to
missional for no heads are pointed out
that protection doesn't just involve
emptiness it also involves dependent
origination which in in normal language
means it doesn't just mean to understand
there's no husband who's not my fault it
also means to understand there is a
husband who is my fault that's dependent
origination if you want to confuse
people call it dependent origination if
you want two people to understand call
it my seeds created my husband okay
same thing sing too okay if you give
long confusing words to the Dharma it
keeps many monks and nuns in business
for a long time including me if you just
use simple language we have to play
rock'n'roll and do something else
okay burner name methane methane member
Mendelssohn novella to look meddlesome
for example you can think of the
relationship that a sick person has to
the doctor to the medicine and to the
nurse or physician yeah okay got it
alright then up on Bobby chill did you
get a cap on my cheekbone are they do it
Kevin Looney tune every time you
understand a new idea of Buddhism you
are protected from one more bad thing
every time you understand a new idea in
Buddhism you are protected from one more
bad thing
okay in this guy we we call it life to
our life idea idea for your life there's
12 in each level so far we have might be
five or six but every time you learn one
of those 95 you protect yourself from
one bad thing okay that's protection
understanding is protection okay that
means by the way that refuge ritual
happens we're in your kitchen in your
heart in your kitchen okay okay it's not
so much when venable Phil gave you vows
or valuable Jigme gave you those it's
the real ritual that confirms you as a
Buddhist happens in the kitchen when
your husband yells at you
okay got it that's the real that's when
you get real refuge Falls
okay always you know you guys are the
next generation of teachers and always
try to think of ways that it doesn't
become a ritual that it becomes
something people use in their home in
their work with their children with
their parents okay like that okay the
fourth section is called taking shelf
taking refuge by not
agreeing to other kinds of protection
okay taking real protection by not
agreeing to lower country protection is
the fourth instruction here okay and
it's reflected in the first message go
okay it doesn't mean you have to swear
you're Buddhist and then if you go to
sneak into a church you're a bad person
or so it doesn't mean that it means
solve your problems with seeds achieve
your goals with seeds and don't waste
your time on other stuff you know first
three course the first thing you try
should be seeds okay then you're a
Buddhist it doesn't mean you can't go to
a doctor okay it also doesn't mean we
don't have to go to work I heard
somebody in China told their parents
geshe michael says I just need seeds and
I don't have to go to work okay the
seeds have to come through something
okay
plant seeds get a job that you enjoy and
you'll be successful okay if you're
super bitter you don't have to go to
work okay but we're not super Bruner
okay all right sheepish and mmm are we
gonna cancel Tony's when gaggle elope
and toasting to obtain so there was two
brothers in India who were Acharya
semesters per year but Dumbo chill
opinion and they started as non-buddhist
if you care one is name would plot the
city Swami and the other is called
Chantel uppity Shankar uppity
[Music]
call me won't you churches so they're
the god of their religion was name Indra
okay and church here we will contain
lisanna and to make offerings to Indra
they they climbed a mountain in the
Himalayas Sir Walter Chambers angular
camp
then they saw India but he was on his
knees taking refuge vows from Buddha
they say well then maybe Kim Britain
what the heck
she take James elope in Chembur Japan
and they became great masters of the
Mahayana teachings they segregate area
into jippy and one of them wrote a
famous poem which is in the tenure
called capita Proctor I I bow to your
greatness or something like that
I belt here extraordinary greatness it's
a very very beautiful poem and it's
often quoted okay all right well great
symbolic emza gentle gentle eloping
mission to Germany Cooper damn Barsoom
Adam ideally we should reach a point
where our understanding is so big that
we're not interested in any other
teacher okay then the Buddha okay and it
doesn't mean you're a bad person if you
like Jesus or Moses or Muhammad it just
means that the more you learn the
stronger you will admire what the good
of time okay they and and my personal
beliefs is targeted for cheaper which is
what a song guitars
which is in the end they all go to the
same place so that's a Buddhist
principle talk to temperature
you know tart tote means in the end tech
bar means past means it's all the same
okay it all dates the same place okay
sometimes are slower sometimes our
father okay a temple on the radiation to
kill me to pretend then you're a refuge
will slowly become stronger and stronger
okay burnt umber textured shed being a
chiller to keep an accounting infinity
the the Buddhist word for non-buddhist
is outsider okay and if you continually
take refuge in science or things that
only work on a surface level then
actually chill to Gilpin you you leave
the Buddhist group you become number
okay in it so it's very tricky you know
when I try to fix the air conditioner by
taking it apart I'm sort of alienating
myself from Buddhism and when I try to
fix the air conditioner as the child
told me to in New York what's his name
Leon's place if I if I go and try to
help someone else with an air
conditioning problem then I confirmed
myself as a Buddhist Booker T ridiculous
number dong-chil a stumbled on Tambor
Don DeLillo beginning and you children
keep on young gay meaning if you want to
kind of get a feeling of the difference
of the Sangha between those who are
trying to fix the air conditioner by
helping father's fix things or those who
are trying to take it apart okay by the
way do you have to take it apart yeah
but it won't get fixed unless you have
someone else okay so you still have to
fix my heart longer okay
that meant umber now I read your poem he
calls at home dog meat amber champagne
me Tom thank you like Elsa cheese they
achieve leader shimmer they Chilean are
cute killing on onion them them I
I'm going to leave other teachers for
for this time I'm going to take refuge
in you Brunner
why because you actually everything you
teach is right and you don't teach
anything wrong
okay got it who wrote that one of the
two brothers okay the brother that he
was talking about that's from his pulse
here's another line from that poem you
take change from Mulan Sita ji Panem
samba take Todd guitar can kill nah
doc is something different girl the more
familiar I become with the teachings of
science etc the more I believe in you
like we don't understand quantum physics
or the general theory of relativity and
so we kind of think they know what
they're talking about because they can
blow up a city but but in if you really
study it if you really really you know
spend a few weeks with Wikipedia by the
annual reach which is named item
Heisenberg's
I'm certainly principle which is not
really his but it's still a core
principle that they don't even know how
life goes from the Sun to the earth they
cannot agree and there's no physical way
to measure correctly how light comes
from the Sun to the earth like a basic
thing how light comes from my face to
your eyes they can't understand they
can't explain it because it acts two
different ways according to to who's
watching
according to who's present light that
goes through a diffraction grating
behaves either as a particle or as a
wave contradictory okay depending on
who's watching okay and if you really
study you come down to that which is the
pen okay all right knocking knock turn
account
here's another poem from another verse
called the praise of people were the
oppressed just on topical I've done good
any among them John come Danny politic
Adam chili chicken chip a lock Oh Oh
Lord Buddha you hero what's the
difference between your teaching and in
the words of other people you tell us
what's good to do and what's wrong to do
what will make us happy and what will
not make us happy and I don't see it
clearly elsewhere
okay that was written by a machine a
multi-chip okay pendulum with egg bun or
medium so there's a word called would
text and we take this is the ancient
Buddhist word for non-buddhist okay and
it was from India and I recently in our
translator class we found we translated
the reason for the word tentacle mythic
and it means people who set up
little stool in the stream so they can
wash away their sins or something like
that
tear touka so PO bunker says the days of
tirthikas are gone we don't see them
into that you know the classical non
Buddhist schools of India are gone you
can go to I spent many years teaching at
Shiva namah Center in Bahamas once a
year are you for 10 years I went there
once a year and they're supposed to be
teaching turcica with Declan
but the but the knowledge is almost gone
that system is almost gone okay it's
actually better in Kolkata he explains
it more clearly when he teaches the
other school okay anyway Chengdu
Shepherd on kappa and ketchup Akashic
Allah - so huh I translated it you may
encounter you account it you need people
who encountered a problem so they got
into some weird stuff it means you meet
these kind of people I don't know I seem
to meet them a lot in yoga classes but
they'll saying you know I just got I
just found out that somebody there was a
snowstorm work where I live and I met
this couple at this coffee shop and they
were they didn't have a place to sleep
because their highway closed so I said
you can stay at my you know I'll find
your place to stay and I found a place
to stay and then they said we have a big
load of ayahuasca in our car and would
you like some and I thought they meant
jicama
which is a vegetable and I said you know
I don't really like it that much and
it's some kind of drug okay it's popular
nowadays it's some kind of plant I think
right and people take it and then it
they think they can see God or something
like that okay it's popular in America
with young people right now and a good
friend of mine Kevin his daughter went
to a ceremony to take it and she died
okay during the ceremony and she had her
phone on
she had her video going and you can see
her die and so these are just people get
into weird things you know people say
all ayahuasca stand there saying you
know the new cool thing she was
beautiful she sang a Madonna during my
three and retreat I remember she in
Celtic I think she she she did the song
and Celtic very beautiful woman very
very beautiful sunny way people get into
weird stuff
young core mangu Padang then they
attract many people because it seems
like they have something special okay
changing monsoon shaders then because
they want to get attention from people
they want people to follow them burned
on monitor looked similar Juba la
jhemini embodied on me so they they
start following some kind of weird like
I don't know I'm going to call that
shaman stuff with high Hrothgar on or
something like that okay and then
everyone runs to the ceremony
the a bunch of people dying in nearest
flexpa summer ceremony in a recall sweat
lodge like how many three people say my
son Raja Bhoja Mohammed II Donnie
Kaplan means in chiba if you if you go
to refuge for something like that like
your drug then you're splitting your
refuge and then it weakens your refuge
okay
or if you split it to science and to see
you know I think 5050 I worked in a
diamond company for you know 19 years
the owner was from Israel and very fine
men and every six months I I will give
half my salary to setting those books
and things like that so he will write a
check from the company as a donation and
then every time he'll say you know I'll
throw in an extra ten thousand for me
you know I'm like wow you know and then
one day I asked him I said why are you
so nice to me know why you always add
money when I make those donation he says
I you never know who's right maybe
Jewish maybe but anyway don't split your
attention okay either extent science you
know or accept seeds science receipts
okay I like to call it accept science or
accept science or seeds
you know accept Aspen it's going to work
by itself all the time which you can see
is not true or accept that Aspen will
work if you serve others
ok got it but don't like say whichever
you know you never know which might be
right kochak bring Ben got Benga chase
Eric any account then he gets into a
delicate question it's a
can you kind of keep some of your old
old beliefs and and and use these new
ones awesome okay so many of us grew up
Christian for example and I'm very happy
with the church and I I had very
beautiful deep experiences in the church
because so then some people will say can
I just do like 50/50 you know a second
young drink Ottumwa done should um JJ's
a super nun like le baguette admitting
then he says examine who it is you're
going for refuge to in that belief and
what protecting you and who's the people
who are going to go on the journey with
you okay what is there Buddha Dharma
Sangha okay studying sin mate a and and
he says and let you have a very deep
understanding in which I believe you can
find those emptiness teachings in other
faiths okay you'll be disappointed okay
in here Dave temple are can cleanse a
sake intendment then
if you don't understand those those
other teachers teachings deeply you you
will be disappointed and you will find
some problems near okay and children
your mom the car dealer took some mitt
and he says an interesting thing and I
kept a teacher in the chain said there
tonight I used to I wrote it down and
kept it on my wall for many years he
said if you're practicing something and
it's not making you happier
year by year then something's wrong okay
if you're practicing something and it's
not making you a better person and
happier year by year then something's
wrong okay even Buddhism even your
participation Jenna mr. Daaga
Temba unicode check on datum geometric a
single I and M asam this is a thing
where in Tibet there was some groups
that were not Buddhist but they wore
Buddhist rows and they have a blue robe
and they have their own culture but if
they stolen it's the Buddhist cogito
with the words with the titles change
you can see sometimes as you check in
they just replaced Buddha's name with
their teacher's name
there are we debated them once they came
only once they came to debate with us
you know we have to say that other
children which means what about this
example of this object and the word is
Dharma
right object is called Dharma and they
refuse to say they said bunch and they
want to say take this but they wouldn't
say take this thing because the word for
thing is also Dharma so they refuse to
say so they would say bunch and we take
churches and then
they only came once okay don't get maybe
so they don't have the vow tradition
unbroken traditional vows that we have
even though they may wear those clothes
that makes you think they might but not
number Camden your method comes to me
the idea of taking refuge by trying to
protect yourself by not answering your
husband when he yells at you right will
refuse they don't have it they don't
have it they say bow down to this God or
bow down to this gun but they don't say
bow down to this idea that you shouldn't
respond to violence with violence
because you created it and you will just
create more okay they don't have this
idea
they say bow down to this statue of
announcer this tension has been built
and repentant charge donkey Tom de la
Garde took the double Mayan bar then he
says I'm not trying to criticize other
religions and I'm not trying to make an
argument I'm just saying there's a
difference between how we bow down to
Buddha and how they bow down to their
holy beans when we bow down to Buddha
it's when we're in the kitchen having a
fight with our husband and it's not in
the temple and and bowing down to some
statue okay it's a different he said
it's just different and if you ask them
do you bow down to the idea that there's
a second husband in the kitchen that's
not there they'll say that's crazy
okay got it right we believe its
protection ultimate protections okay
all right one drink a big singin go get
em denim night to Metabo geekland jinda
Jin Shepherd shepherd couch anyway then
he says in the case of
this ancient shamanism of Tibet you
should check out also where it developed
and how it's gone because there are
books about that explained how it
developed and how it started to kendama
budgets into total jiggy cool don't they
to do to Timberlake she's shocky menos
ownership agree then there are books in
Tibet called Siddhanta been Cramer's
translating one for our translation from
them and they explained the sources and
the beliefs of this ancient school okay
I was teaching Hindu people Sankhya
people their school in their ashram
because they didn't understand and talk
about a beautiful chapter about the
police of Sankhya system advisor and it
was cool you know they lost a lot of
their beliefs and forgot I recorded them
okay then I forgive them but there but
our son calls cheated GOG on Sephardim
so this basically to put it into modern
terms the ideas of science infects
everything we do okay everything we
believe all the things we do during the
day we are trusting the idea that
chemicals are the building block of
reality we that's our viewpoint
everybody in this room
cellphone mentality children are going
to have none none basing them Mary
Parker digs into Java so to Ching now
machine a Jinbei but a lot of the
beliefs that are in India and Tibet came
from early Buddhism if you read the yoga
Sutra and I memorized it
my screen Irma tree it's a
conglomeration of Buddhism from the
third century okay it's just a bunch of
ideas from Buddhism put in one book
[Music]
Kappa Delta Cupid the mint Godwin yungay
then those become systems in themselves
and then they get very weird
commentaries try to read a modern
commentary the yoga Sutra do a do- it
capsule but darn you turn their way
naming in they're not going to protect
you okay they're not going to help you
with your husband in the kitchen they're
not going to help you with your business
problems you know they're not going to
help you meditate then TED talk like
Gandhi Jayanthi think gumbo then there
was a famous person who started a
lineage into that called jiggle in his
name was rin-chan pal Roberto bunkie
Kutner cheat on chef Dominick yet I know
so they have us they have a belief in
India
it's called Aspergillus come under under
judge the world was born from a cosmic
egg okay it's in the how do you was a
difficulty not like a little child and
then this custom of making sacrifices
killing cows for religion killing lamps
for to take away the sins of Jerusalem
which is funny because it just adds to
the sins of Jerusalem won't you sake
chip it looks and no num these ideas
muta guitar Calloway and they're all
mixed up with different we call it
primitive belief Kadam Virgili
this is from a book
a famous book of the Kadamba who are the
first Goodison to bed and this is book
is a couple of thousand pages long and
Nick's group just had it import they
finished it last week I'd like to thank
you it's the most important book from
the early days of Buddhism in Tibet
thousand years ago called Kadam McDonald
and we couldn't find it for a long time
and I just finished it about a week ago
I think it has an important part of the
Wheel of Life so I was trying to find it
ok it it is the teaching of the wheel of
life as we know it today for the first
time it changed when our teacher came to
Tibet moontak burning Medina
tell God to sing and Orchard buddha
purnima donned our ginseng now in danger
now
yep I could not sleep again so things
like hi Alaska ceremonies they might
make you feel cool I took it once ok to
be honest not Hiawatha I took masculine
in a K and I went to a canyon Inn near
near Cottonwood there's a beautiful
secret Canyon when I was like 19 I went
there and there's a beautiful river and
case and it's totally isolated and very
beautiful and I stayed for a couple days
and I took mescaline and all this stuff
happened to me I thought I heard the
angel singing and I was jumping over
cliff one clip to another clear enough
you know I was like oh this is so cool
you know in any way in the short run for
a few hours for a few days
you might see something cool and the
first time I met the guy llama I think I
was with my mom yeah my mom was dying
and my mama took me there she was dying
for his blessing and he said
so I'm sitting with my mom and he looks
me in the eye and the first thing he
says is did you ever take drugs and I'm
like yeah my mom like talked about it
it means hear what they're talking about
is there are things you can do which
make you feel happy for a few days or a
few hours and then you come back worse
than before okay so there are drugs you
can do this hippy things you can do
don't eat for ten days you know strange
things and it will make you feel happy
for a couple hours or a couple of days
and then in the long run it will ruin
your life okay and those of you who've
tried jobs you know that I'm kind of
glad I tried them I'm glad I didn't
become a monk till I was 30 because I
tried everything okay I know everything
okay
now Jackie wants you and Jamie Lachey
mahjongg will go for another 15 minutes
or so okay you chat like supposed to be
funny
maybe he looked at Singapore during the
three days yeah exactly want to sell he
quotes Milarepa who's the most famous
meditator from today bondage uncle of
chittim node on jumbo top thanking Chapa
total normative punishing to my parents
so this these ideas
of like Hiawatha ceremonies things like
that local spirits trusting local
experience it's not an ultimate solution
it's not a long-term solution
Shin Dong Eponine cab McDonnell of
the world the difference between
Buddhism and other beliefs is the
husband in the kitchen okay that's all
we take refuge we seek protection in the
idea that all fears and all negative
things that come to us are because we
hurt somebody in the past and we have to
purify them that's our belief we take
refuge in not repeating the same mistake
number Kevin a courtesan she bets on
long can you go running : journey
shadowing new Bernie and something
something new you know to to take people
out of suffering you should have done it
for yourself once we love that you think
are wrong young con watching your pay
Shindler so don't you know don't spend a
lot of time following something made by
people who are not happy and who are
suffering like scientists okay alright
in the end they die and they and they've
gone and and it didn't help them okay
all that science didn't help them
chicken Tinga Bayesian on negative
tongue so under qatar by number two
economy
can't give you your mana much less
bruticon what's the difference what's
nirvana I like to define nirvana
nobody can excuse me I'm not going to
say a bad word my Lama said nothing
nobody can make you angry anymore
you're at nirvana okay if you know all
things you're at enlightenment okay
that's a difference so those other paths
can't even give you the lower goal of
Nirvana
okay number come como las on the Ragman
Lukey Kim hunter sangeeta burger - no
you need inner sanctum then there are
some people who go for refuge in local
spirits one of my Lamas said we have a
spring here okay bear Springs why's it
called Bear Springs we have bears then I
don't know if you have time you should
go see it it's next to the lama house up
there community when you call ranch
house it's in front of the ranch house
there's a natural water it's one of the
only ones in Arizona shelter and summer
and that's why they built this there's a
military fort here that's 100 100 years
old Conan City and to protect to take
the water from the local people so
anyway one of my llamas said there's a
Naga here there's our spirit water
spirit here and for many years the water
stopped it started last year again is it
still going yeah you can go see it it's
very deep it will cover your toes
there is no to that that's cruel
all right anyway those kind of creatures
that we can't see spirits you know
they're not going to help you get
nirvana relations okay
so just you zimba know okay don't waste
your time tanks on Carcetti prankish an
LA economy generates it on chicken same
chant undecided do join which is
sangwich I think youtuber mumble thank
you Jason
then some people said to palanca they
said look I think like these Hindu gods
or Christian God or Muslim gods I think
they are Buddha they are Buddha they are
just Buddha in different form seven
times a is taking the Google imager and
then every person on this planet is a
disciple of the Buddha okay sanguine
chance angry to bernabéu computation to
me so it's possible that our body
suffers and boodles in every minute we
bla know Chapel I end my talk in master
William
Bethel morning long mr. talkie part
remember Gil nefesh HL mumblety-peg Tom
chamber she think that may be true okay
but if there if there a system that you
can use to become a Buddha in that
belief this their way where they explain
the pen and they explain how to get
protection you know it's okay but but if
there is there the teaching there that
people can use for their real life
victim - again chan-sung key trip again
do not go internship egg then then it
makes a joke if you don't care whether
they're teaching protection or not then
since dogs and
roaches might also be Brutus you can
just take refuge in them and keep them
at their give minute but it won't help
you that the dog and become roaches
can't explain to you about anything they
can't explain the pen to you okay there
so it's possible everyone you mean it's
a burner but not everybody is teaching
the pen okay something that can protect
you so it's probably better to stick to
the one who is explaining the pen okay
and when house I was home she big
shindig for me okay excuse me
I didn't write the book okay but I
should read every sentence to you he
said you come into that they didn't have
toilet paper so people would use rocks
with a sharp little bit sharp edge but
not too sharp and he says after you wipe
your butt with one of those but rocks
you don't take it home and put it you
know keep it like this you know you just
enjoy it okay so it's possible and
Tantra says there are holy beings all
around us okay it's possible but for us
who's teaching you about the husband in
the kitchen that's where we should go
right now you know at our level that's
what we need right now there may be a
day when we can sit with some end I also
looked at ants in my retreat my
three-year retreat because there wasn't
anything else to do
and it's very impossible someday you'll
reach a place where they you realize
those anti Buddha it's possible there
will come a day but to get there we need
to study the pan that we have to go to
classes and we have to we have to learn
all these things and things that don't
teach you about the pen you should throw
away like but Rach
we keep looking for a name for our band
not a good language ok numbers I gave it
Capricornus in Conan our cameraman to
sing the link on cable today so you can
put your trust in in this Buddhist
refuge try it out you know next time you
have a problem with somebody somebody
hurts you next time somebody hurts here
can not buy way not because it's
spiritual not because it's spiritual but
because it's effective because it works
then try to remember they're coming from
you ok not because it makes you a
beautiful spiritual person it will make
you a beautiful spiritual person but
that's not why take refuge because it
works it helps if you don't respond to
the husband or criticizes you with
criticism then over time what it must
surely be MSA if you if you keep up this
habit what did he say yeah you're going
to miss them you're going to say how
come no I don't have anybody to practice
with anymore
we used to have all those guys helping
out at Diamond Mountain who pissed me
off and now they're all gone you know
like I really can't I don't get many
opportunities nowadays that people give
you opportunities to practice will get
fewer and fewer because you're not
responding you're not planning these
things okay just try see what works okay
okay donut come down it's sick the
bottom line is said King maintain
contact between the captain with them
don't and then we'll stop one more
sentence okay don't let your refuge be
something you do in the class when
you're done talking you don't know me
okay don't let it be a thoughtless word
try to take refuge like a criminal who's
facing the death sentence and they are
they get one chance to appear before a
judge who can let them go in America
there's this custom right the governor
of the state can sign a paper and even
the guy who's supposed to be killed will
will be not killed okay Carola can so
try to imagine when you take refuge that
you're like the guy who's going to be
killed tomorrow by the court and you
have one chance to talk to the judge and
and and and and take refuge with that
kind of respect you know I'm not really
a bad person
you take refuge a little bit seriously
don't don't like this I get you know me
and some dark or less all HEK because
that judge can protect you from going to
hell and animal realms after you die
that judges who
it's not even the three jewels which
jewel damage on okay we had a long
teaching about it in Diamond Mountain
last time okay when you understand the
pet to a certain degree it's not
possible to go to the lower realm and
people complain when I repeated one guy
not you but we're going to Singapore on
there from you so you taught that last
time then I'm I don't want to tell him
now I'm trying to keep you out of the
hell I'm like all really I'm so sorry
you know Kela Kelln every chain you name
for me from the ender devil took a chat
with them but this is part of the
definition of refuge means put all your
hopes in what in that response to your
health
okay put all your hopes in that response
to your husband not some God okay it's
an idea that's protection I told you
before I'll tell you again man with a
famous intimate during the Buddhist life
his village was attacked people came and
ran to him they held on to his lower row
for protection and they were killed the
blood was all over his room you know
they couldn't kill him but they killed
all the people okay
taking refuge is not holding some
Buddhists out to you or or praying to
some picture of Buddha
that's not Buddhist refuge this is
Buddhist refuge don't answer your
husband because you don't want to plant
another one like that okay all right
that's protection okay simply a
submachine the chamber today they needed
some key counsel some say in so you know
you've taken refuge when you trust that
idea okay that's refuge when you don't
respond to violence with violence
you took refuge okay got it all right
doesn't mean you shouldn't go to the
ceremony with that venerable Phil and
venerable Jigme huh
ha that's not Refuge you should go okay
yeah it's making a beautiful commitment
and then you should remember that
commitment when you go to your kids
I can't got it both is okay Anton yes
Russell hang on one second
we just want to there's people listening
in in Bowie I think itõs efrati the
absolutions time thank you so when we
deal with a big situation like yelling
husband and we're thinking about taking
the refuge and we take it but when we do
a small thing for example when I go from
this place to to the wall so my steps
are not the cause for me to reach the
one to reach the wall that's correct but
should I do making this section should I
keep remembering that this not because
and if I'm not doing it doing actually
when the Bad Seeds of not understanding
or taking the refuge
what's the healthy like what's the fine
line when you should actually take the
normal action or when you should take
refuge yeah it happens to me when I turn
on a light you know like I reach out to
the light and I touch it and I'm like
it doesn't make the light go on it you
know I think these things let go and
then I go like that it goes on but
sometimes it doesn't right
Vivian so I think there's a balance the
more aware you can be the more you get
protections but you know those of you
who did three-year retreat there's days
when you walk around like nerds you know
yeah I'm going to take residence I'm
just going to the toilet but I don't
remember what it was you know I mean you
can get spaced out you know I think you
can be dysfunctional I mean if you did a
three retreat there's days when you're
you're so center pivot if you're too
sensitive and then you can't help people
you can't relate to people you know so I
think it's a balance I think it's a
balance but it doesn't hurt to try to do
it when you turn on the lights or you
know I want to get food so you open the
fridge but that's not how you get food
right so just to remember that from time
to time in a healthy way
we'll make you a kinder and kind of
person but if it starts to make you like
you can't tie your shoes then then you
should back off a little bit seriously
because like you know we've all seen
Dharma people who get dysfunctional
that's not the goal oh cool
yeah wait
microphone he goes back to the air
conditioner at that point you had to fix
the air conditioner and the little boy
said no both fix someone else's could
you not at that point use the four
powers and bring up a memory of a time
when you helped someone maybe actually
help someone fix an air conditioner and
can you not do a meditation and have
that be the the way of fixing them yeah
that's a great suggestion I mean it
would take an hour to find someone else
on 15 in New York who who had a almost
Indian restaurants that aren't there
anymore
as you're done editing are broken then
then say no and if the kids with their
parents would come to pick up their kids
we wouldnt have a class so yeah I think
that's a great idea you know in theory
you lived countless life so you have
seats for everything in the bank and we
teach in DCI we teach sometimes you know
in theory you have enough speech in your
mind already to be Warren Buffett you
know you just didn't activate them
you didn't rejoice in them so for me to
be honest
rather than for power I'm a bad person I
didn't make other people cool you know
I'm sorry it doesn't work so good for me
I like something positive and I I must
have fixed some goddamn person's air
conditioning you know like a three
billion years ago and so I redoing
that I helped someone fix their
condition and I think that and it works
and it's pretty cool so you can do that
you have lots of unused seats in your
mind
countless if you could access them you
would be successful without much Newark
which is always attractive to me okay
all right